<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Josh Werts</title>
    <link>http://joshwerts.com/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Josh Werts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 18:17:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://joshwerts.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Octopress to Hexo to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://joshwerts.com/blog/2015/12/10/octopress-to-hexo-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 18:17:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joshwerts.com/blog/2015/12/10/octopress-to-hexo-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This blog post is really just to say &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow! Hugo is freakin&amp;rsquo; awesome!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-href-http-octopress-org-octopress-a:955d799df0aa29831b7762c00172d370&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://joshwerts.com/img/octopress.png&#34; alt=&#34;Octopress&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress definitely got the job done and introduced me to static blog generators, but I had no real desire to learn Ruby and lately with Windows 10, I&amp;rsquo;ve booted up to Linux less and less (yes, Windows 10 really is pretty good - if only it had a bash terminal).  Installing Ruby on Windows just wasn&amp;rsquo;t something I wanted to bother with.  Also, if I wanted to change the underlying templates, it just seemed more complicated than it really needed to be and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the time or motivation to really bother changing the default template much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-href-https-hexo-io-hexo-a:955d799df0aa29831b7762c00172d370&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hexo.io/&#34;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://joshwerts.com/img/hexo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hexo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soooooooo&amp;hellip; the next logical step seemed to be Hexo.  NodeJS - easy enough on Windows and I&amp;rsquo;ve done a little node development here and there so here we go.  Somehow this just seemed a bit kludgy too.  It&amp;rsquo;s a decent enough project, but just didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-href-https-gohugo-io-hugo-a:955d799df0aa29831b7762c00172d370&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://joshwerts.com/img/hugo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for excuses to learn Go, so on a whim, googled static blog generators and Go.  I&amp;rsquo;m yet to really learn any Go from using Hugo (other than perusing the code), but still it&amp;rsquo;s nice to know it&amp;rsquo;s there if I need to dig through source to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s up or want to dive deeper and contribute to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, Hugo &lt;em&gt;just feels right.&lt;/em&gt;  Not only was I able to migrate my existing blog fairly quickly, but it was not only easy, but also &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; to start hacking on an existing theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasons I love Hugo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation is just a matter of adding a .exe to your PATH and your good to go.  Can&amp;rsquo;t argue with that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good documentation - was fairly easy to get started (one hint though: you need to specify a theme or it will seem like it&amp;rsquo;s failing silently)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go templates seem mostly straightforward and powerful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPEED&lt;/strong&gt; - this wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a criteria for me since this blog is pretty small but with Hugo&amp;rsquo;s speed (100ms to generate this blog) along with its &lt;strong&gt;built-in live reload&lt;/strong&gt;, development is easy and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is currently running off a moderately modified &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/digitalcraftsman/hugo-steam-theme&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; theme.  Development is fun enough that hopefully it will continue to evolve (in other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;fighting the framework&lt;/em&gt; with Hugo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found these resources especially helpful for migration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nathanleclaire.com/blog/2014/12/22/migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress/&#34;&gt;http://nathanleclaire.com/blog/2014/12/22/migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>